<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Craftsmanship on Sebiwi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software-craftsmanship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Craftsmanship on Sebiwi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 07:19:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software-craftsmanship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Operations, DevOps and soft skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-operations-devops-and-soft-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 07:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-operations-devops-and-soft-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-talk-about-communication-for-a-bit&#34;&gt;Let’s talk about communication for a bit.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting roles I’ve had to fulfill the last couple of years&#xA;has been the “Operations guy working as a part of a Development team”. This is&#xA;a fascinating situation to find yourself in. Allow me to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Operations teams have been isolated from Development teams. &lt;strong&gt;Two&#xA;separate organizational entities&lt;/strong&gt;. The reasons for this were manifold:&#xA;Operations people were a scarce resource, they needed to accommodate vast&#xA;amounts of work for numerous Development teams (server provisioning for team A,&#xA;middleware configuration for team B, application deployment for team C), it&#xA;made sense for management to group people into teams using their skillset as&#xA;sorting criteria&amp;hellip; you name it. In the end, most interactions between&#xA;Development teams and Operation teams happened through ticketing systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Craftsmanship and OPS scripting: a love story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-craftsmanship-and-ops-scripting-a-love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 07:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-craftsmanship-and-ops-scripting-a-love-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was co-written by the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.octo.com/author/tanguy-patte-tpa/&#34;&gt;Tanguy Patte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alright, story time fellas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re working with Terraform, layering and workspaces. This makes the standard&#xA;&lt;code&gt;terraform workspace select x&lt;/code&gt; pretty cumbersome and dangerous. We wrote a Ruby&#xA;wrapper using Test-Driven Development. It allows us to have a tested,&#xA;maintainable and efficient solution to the aforementioned issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the actual project here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebiwi/terraform-wrapper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sebiwi/terraform-wrapper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you keep reading, we’re going to talk about scripting, Test-Driven&#xA;Development, Terraform and Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Scenarios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-just-dont-know-how-to-do-it&#34;&gt;You just don’t know how to do it.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’ve been thinking about it for a while too. It’s an important issue. The&#xA;crafting of the spell is the most important part. The journey is usually more&#xA;important than the destination itself. But you don’t feel like you are doing it&#xA;right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose is simple, yet it has a duality of character. You want to enable&#xA;the transmission of information between all realms into a single library of&#xA;knowledge. A task you’ve already accomplished many times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Side effects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-side-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-side-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;he-has-questions&#34;&gt;He has questions.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, he has not yet arrived. And you know you have answers. You&#xA;interrupt your summoning, and sit down. You can continue in another moment.&#xA;Everything happens for a reason. You just hope the reason is good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N appears right next to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hey, what’s up?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m setting up the auto-scaling configuration of the new project. Nothing huge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cool. I need some help.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has progressed immensely since the last time you saw him. People are&#xA;starting to ask him for help now. You can’t help but feel pride when you see&#xA;what he has become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Ansible, Molecule and Test Driven Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-ansible-molecule-and-test-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-ansible-molecule-and-test-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;magic-has-existed-since-the-dawn-of-time&#34;&gt;Magic has existed since the dawn of time.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has always been there, hidden in plain sight, making amazing things possible&#xA;for those willing to open their eyes and harness its power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t remember the first time you used it, and yet it feels like you&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;never existed without it. You&amp;rsquo;ve obliterated endless armies of enemies by&#xA;virtue of spells and enchantments, and you&amp;rsquo;ve also constructed awe-inspiring&#xA;marvels from the ground up. As a result, you&amp;rsquo;re renowned for your overwhelming&#xA;powers in every single one of your incarnations through time. Everyone knows&#xA;about &lt;strong&gt;the Wizard&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
