<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Sebiwi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Sebiwi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 07:19:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Operations, DevOps and soft skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-operations-devops-and-soft-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 07:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/on-operations-devops-and-soft-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-talk-about-communication-for-a-bit&#34;&gt;Let’s talk about communication for a bit.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting roles I’ve had to fulfill the last couple of years&#xA;has been the “Operations guy working as a part of a Development team”. This is&#xA;a fascinating situation to find yourself in. Allow me to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historically, Operations teams have been isolated from Development teams. &lt;strong&gt;Two&#xA;separate organizational entities&lt;/strong&gt;. The reasons for this were manifold:&#xA;Operations people were a scarce resource, they needed to accommodate vast&#xA;amounts of work for numerous Development teams (server provisioning for team A,&#xA;middleware configuration for team B, application deployment for team C), it&#xA;made sense for management to group people into teams using their skillset as&#xA;sorting criteria&amp;hellip; you name it. In the end, most interactions between&#xA;Development teams and Operation teams happened through ticketing systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Craftsmanship and OPS scripting: a love story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-craftsmanship-and-ops-scripting-a-love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 07:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-craftsmanship-and-ops-scripting-a-love-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was co-written by the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.octo.com/author/tanguy-patte-tpa/&#34;&gt;Tanguy Patte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alright, story time fellas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re working with Terraform, layering and workspaces. This makes the standard&#xA;&lt;code&gt;terraform workspace select x&lt;/code&gt; pretty cumbersome and dangerous. We wrote a Ruby&#xA;wrapper using Test-Driven Development. It allows us to have a tested,&#xA;maintainable and efficient solution to the aforementioned issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the actual project here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebiwi/terraform-wrapper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sebiwi/terraform-wrapper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you keep reading, we’re going to talk about scripting, Test-Driven&#xA;Development, Terraform and Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Container: Chronicle of a death foretold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ansible-container-chronicle-of-a-death-foretold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ansible-container-chronicle-of-a-death-foretold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was co-written by the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.octo.com/author/adrien-besnard-bes/&#34;&gt;Adrien Besnard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alright, here’s what’s up:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We tried Ansible Container. We’d rather keep using Dockerfiles for image&#xA;builds: creating a Docker image and provisioning servers with Ansible are two&#xA;very different things. Different in terms of lifecycle, philosophy and&#xA;workflow. So different, that in our opinion, they’re not compatible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wanna know why? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer! While the current status of Ansible Container is not clear, it&#xA;seems that during the writing of this article the tool has &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ansible/ansible-container/commit/2fa778a7c8d1699672314ac0b89c53554f435cb7&#34;&gt;been deprecated&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;After the limitations we noticed, we won&amp;rsquo;t say that we didn&amp;rsquo;t see that&#xA;coming&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Scenarios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-just-dont-know-how-to-do-it&#34;&gt;You just don’t know how to do it.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’ve been thinking about it for a while too. It’s an important issue. The&#xA;crafting of the spell is the most important part. The journey is usually more&#xA;important than the destination itself. But you don’t feel like you are doing it&#xA;right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose is simple, yet it has a duality of character. You want to enable&#xA;the transmission of information between all realms into a single library of&#xA;knowledge. A task you’ve already accomplished many times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Side effects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-side-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-side-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;he-has-questions&#34;&gt;He has questions.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, he has not yet arrived. And you know you have answers. You&#xA;interrupt your summoning, and sit down. You can continue in another moment.&#xA;Everything happens for a reason. You just hope the reason is good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N appears right next to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hey, what’s up?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m setting up the auto-scaling configuration of the new project. Nothing huge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cool. I need some help.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has progressed immensely since the last time you saw him. People are&#xA;starting to ask him for help now. You can’t help but feel pride when you see&#xA;what he has become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes vs Docker: Volumes!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-volumes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was co-written by the amazing Pierre-Yves Napoly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-everybody&#34;&gt;Hey everybody!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After reading both the Kubernetes and Docker “How does it work?” series, I&#xA;suess you can’t wait to transform your old-school infrastructure and put&#xA;all your applications inside containers. Indeed, containers are a great way to&#xA;make your applications portable and easy to deploy. Nevertheless, there is a&#xA;subject we have not discussed yet: data persistence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we start, we’d like to say that there are ways to handle data that are&#xA;more cloud-oriented than volumes. These include managed relational database&#xA;services, non-relational database services, and object storage services, all of&#xA;which are easier to operate than volumes, since they harness most of the&#xA;benefits of the cloud ecosystem. Volumes seem to match better &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.octo.com/en/pet-vs-cattle-from-server-craftsman-to-software-craftsman/&#34;&gt;with pets than&#xA;with cattle&lt;/a&gt; and may be an obstacle to scalability unless you are using read&#xA;only volumes (more on this later). In any case, be sure to regularly backup&#xA;your data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard: Ansible, Molecule and Test Driven Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-ansible-molecule-and-test-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-wizard-ansible-molecule-and-test-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;magic-has-existed-since-the-dawn-of-time&#34;&gt;Magic has existed since the dawn of time.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has always been there, hidden in plain sight, making amazing things possible&#xA;for those willing to open their eyes and harness its power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t remember the first time you used it, and yet it feels like you&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;never existed without it. You&amp;rsquo;ve obliterated endless armies of enemies by&#xA;virtue of spells and enchantments, and you&amp;rsquo;ve also constructed awe-inspiring&#xA;marvels from the ground up. As a result, you&amp;rsquo;re renowned for your overwhelming&#xA;powers in every single one of your incarnations through time. Everyone knows&#xA;about &lt;strong&gt;the Wizard&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansible reporting with ARA: Ansible Run Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ansible-reporting-with-ara-ansible-run-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ansible-reporting-with-ara-ansible-run-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a Slack conversation with some friends from work (&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;)&#xA;the other day. It went somewhat like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;“Hey, have you guys ever heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ara.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;ARA&lt;/a&gt;?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was followed by 5 minutes of the deafening sound of contextualisation and&#xA;Google searches by everyone on the channel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;“Nope, but every piece of technology that could enable Ansible to catch&#xA;up with PuppetDB/Board would be very much appreciated”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Docker! Episode 5 - Get some work(ers) done!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-5-get-some-workers-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-5-get-some-workers-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-are-my-workers-man&#34;&gt;Where are my Workers man?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, workers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same procedure as before: main, configure and test.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to configure the Worker node, we will first check if Swarm&#xA;mode is already activated, like we did on the previous roles. If it&#xA;is, we won’t do squat. If it isn’t, we will go fetch the token needed&#xA;to join the cluster as a Worker node from the Leader node, and then&#xA;join the cluster as a Worker node. You should know that the token used&#xA;in order to join the cluster as a Worker node is different from the&#xA;one user to join it as a non-Leader Manager node. So:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Docker! Episode 4 - Control your Swarm!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-4-control-your-swarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-4-control-your-swarm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-please&#34;&gt;Code, please!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yay, code!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, we will need the actual virtual machines where our&#xA;cluster will run. We will create these using Vagrant. If you don’t&#xA;know what Vagrant is, or why are we using it, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sebiwi.github.io/blog/how-does-it-work-kube-3/&#34;&gt;check out this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this deployment, we will have three Manager nodes, and three&#xA;worker nodes.  Why three Manager nodes you say? It may seem overkill,&#xA;but in order to have High Availability you need to have an odd number&#xA;of Manager nodes, otherwise, you will not get consensus from Raft. We&#xA;will see this in action later on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Docker! Episode 3 - Swarm load balancing, service discovery and security</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-3-swarm-load-balancing-service-discovery-and-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-3-swarm-load-balancing-service-discovery-and-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-service-discovery&#34;&gt;Why Service Discovery?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, Service Discovery. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sebiwi.github.io/blog/how-does-it-work-kube-2/&#34;&gt;From a previous article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“...What if your application needs to advertise its own IP address to&#xA;a container that is hosted on another node? It doesn’t actually knows&#xA;its real IP, since his local IP is getting translated into another IP&#xA;and a port on the host machine. ”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s why&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Docker Engine has an embedded DNS server within it, which is used by&#xA;containers when Docker is not running in Swarm mode, and for tasks, when it is.&#xA;It provides name resolution to all the containers that are on the host in&#xA;bridge, overlay or MACVLAN networks. Each container forwards its queries to the&#xA;Docker Engine, which in turn checks if the container or service is on the same&#xA;network as the container that sent the request in the first place. If it is, it&#xA;searches the IP (or virtual IP) address that matches a container, a task’s or a&#xA;service’s name in its internal key-value store and returns it to the container&#xA;that sent the request. Pretty cool, huh?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Docker! Episode 2 - Swarm networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-2-swarm-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-2-swarm-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-about-networking-then&#34;&gt;So what about networking then?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, networking. From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sebiwi.github.io/blog/how-does-it-work-kube-2/&#34;&gt;previous article on Kubernetes&#xA;Networking&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“For each container that is created, a virtual ethernet device is&#xA;attached to this bridge, which is then mapped to eth0 inside the&#xA;container, with an ip within the aforementioned network range. Note&#xA;that this will happen for each host that is running Docker, without&#xA;any coordination between the hosts.  Therefore, the network ranges&#xA;might collide.&#xA;&#xA;Because of this, containers will only be able to communicate with&#xA;containers that are connected to the same virtual bridge. In order to&#xA;communicate with other containers on other hosts, they must rely on&#xA;port-mapping. This means that you need to assign a port on the host&#xA;machine to each container, and then somehow forward all traffic on&#xA;that port to that container. What if your application needs to&#xA;advertise its own IP address to a container that is hosted on another&#xA;node? It doesn’t actually knows its real IP, since his local IP is&#xA;getting translated into another IP and a port on the host machine. You&#xA;can automate the port-mapping, but things start to get kinda complex&#xA;when following this model.&#xA;&#xA;That’s why Kubernetes chose simplicity and skipped the dynamic&#xA;port-allocation deal. It just assumes that all containers can&#xA;communicate with each other without Network Address Translation (NAT),&#xA;that all containers can communicate with each node (and vice-versa),&#xA;and that the IP that a container sees for itself is the same that the&#xA;other containers see for it”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker doesn’t do this. They just went nuts and decided to go crazy on the&#xA;dynamic port-forwarding part. For this, they relied heavily on the existing&#xA;Linux kernel’s networking stack. This is fairly cool, since the existing Linux&#xA;networking features are pretty mature and robust already.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Docker! Episode 1 - Swarm general architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-1-swarm-general-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-docker-episode-1-swarm-general-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hacked another thing together, this time in order to install a highly available&#xA;Docker Swarm cluster on CoreOS (yeah, Container Linux), using Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to try it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git clone https://github.com/sebiwi/docker-coreos.git&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cd docker-coreos&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;make up&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will need Ansible 2.2+, Docker, Vagrant and Molecule&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sebiwi.github.io/blog/how-does-it-work-kube-1/&#34;&gt;I did the same thing with Kubernetes a while ago&lt;/a&gt;, because I wanted to test&#xA;all the different new Kubernetes features and have a local cluster to play with.&#xA;I wanted to do and have the same thing with Docker in Swarm mode. I’m also&#xA;planning on comparing both of them eventually. So I needed the whole prime&#xA;matter first: installation procedures, general architecture, networking model,&#xA;concepts and abstractions and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enforcing strict EC2 instance tagging policies with Lambda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/enforcing-strict-ec2-instance-tagging-policies-with-lambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/enforcing-strict-ec2-instance-tagging-policies-with-lambda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I coded something in order to enforce strict tagging policies on AWS EC2 instances using&#xA;Python and a bunch of AWS services (Lambda, Cloudtrail, SNS, and S3). &lt;strong&gt;If you keep reading,&#xA;I’m going to talk to you about AWS Lambda and Serverless computing, or FaaS (Function as a service).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can check the source code and permission related template files here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://github.com/sebiwi/broom&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use it, create a Cloudtrail trail, activate it on every region, create an S3 bucket&#xA;to store the Cloudtrail logs, create a SNS topic for notifications, create a Lambda function using&#xA;the Python code (adapted to your resources and use case), an IAM role using the policy that comes&#xA;with it, and finally activate events from the S3 bucket to the Lambda function on object creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Kubernetes! Episode 5 - Master and worker, at last!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-5-master-and-worker-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-5-master-and-worker-at-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-install-our-master-node&#34;&gt;Let’s install our Master node!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So basically, we need to create an API server, a Scheduler, and a Controller Manager&#xA;Server on the Master node.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we&amp;rsquo;ll add the TLS resources needed for the master node. That means the CA&#xA;certificate and the API server certificate and key. Nothing complicated about that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next up, networking. For this we&amp;rsquo;ll use Flannel and Calico.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to configure Flannel, we just add configuration environment variables under&#xA;&lt;code&gt;/etc/flannel/options.env&lt;/code&gt;. These specify that the flannel interface is this node&amp;rsquo;s public&#xA;IP, and that the cluster configuration is stocked in etcd cluster:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Kubernetes! Episode 4 - How to Ansible your CoreOS, and etc(d)!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-4-how-to-ansible-your-coreos-and-etcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-4-how-to-ansible-your-coreos-and-etcd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-i-see-the-code-now&#34;&gt;Can I see the code now?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, code. The first step is to actually create the CoreOS virtual machines. I used a really&#xA;simple Vagrantfile in which I specify how many instances I want, and how much computing&#xA;resources each one of them is going to have:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34; data-lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# General cluster configuration&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$etcd_instances &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$etcd_instance_memory &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1024&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$etcd_instance_cpus &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_master_instances &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_master_instance_memory &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2048&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_master_instance_cpus &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_worker_instances &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_worker_instance_memory &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2048&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$kube_worker_instance_cpus &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebiwi/kubernetes-coreos/blob/master/Vagrantfile#L4-L13&#34;&gt;Amazing complexity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can modify the amount of instances you want to create in this part. Be aware that if you&#xA;add hosts, you will also need to add them in the inventory for the Ansible code to target&#xA;all the machines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Kubernetes! Episode 3 - Infrastructure as code: the tools of the trade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-3-infrastructure-as-code-the-tools-of-the-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-3-infrastructure-as-code-the-tools-of-the-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-understand-the-sdn-related-issues-tell-me-about-infrastructure-as-code-already&#34;&gt;I understand the SDN-related issues. Tell me about Infrastructure as Code already!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alright. Whenever I think about automating the creation of a platform or an application&#xA;using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_Code&#34;&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a&gt;, I think about three different stages: provisioning,&#xA;configuration and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisioning&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of creating the virtual resources in which your application&#xA;or platform will run. The complexity of the resources may vary depending on your platform:&#xA;from simple virtual machines if you&amp;rsquo;re working locally, to something slightly more elaborate&#xA;if you&amp;rsquo;re working on the cloud (network resources, firewalls, and various other services).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Kubernetes! Episode 2 - Kubernetes networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-2-kubernetes-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-2-kubernetes-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-dont-even-understand-what-the-problem-is-dude&#34;&gt;I don’t even understand what the problem is dude&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, as I said in the previous article, communication between pods that are&#xA;hosted on different machines can be a little bit tricky. Docker will create by&#xA;default a virtual bridge called “docker0” on the host machine, and it will assign&#xA;a private network range to it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/how-does-it-work-kube/2/docker-bridge.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker bridge&#34;&gt;{: class=&amp;ldquo;bigger-image&amp;rdquo; }&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Super bridge (172.17.0.1/16)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For each container that is created, a virtual ethernet device is attached to this bridge,&#xA;which is then mapped to eth0 inside the container, with an ip within the aforementioned network range.&#xA;Note that this will happen for each host that is running Docker, without any coordination between&#xA;the hosts. Therefore, the network ranges might collide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does it work? Kubernetes! Episode 1 - Kubernetes general architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-1-kubernetes-general-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 20:19:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-does-it-work-kubernetes-episode-1-kubernetes-general-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-everybody&#34;&gt;Hey everybody&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hacked something together in order to create a Kubernetes cluster on CoreOS&#xA;(or Container Linux) using Vagrant and Ansible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you keep reading, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about Kubernetes, etcd, CoreOS, flannel,&#xA;Calico, Infrastructure as Code and Ansible testing strategies. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be super fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The whole subject was way too long for a single article. Therefore, I’ve divided it into 5 parts.&#xA;This is episode 1, regarding the Kubernetes general architecture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fpaste-cli: Share content with magic and style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/fpaste-cli-share-content-with-magic-and-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:50:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/fpaste-cli-share-content-with-magic-and-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-people&#34;&gt;Hey people,&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hacked something together in order to highlight text and send it automatically to fpaste, then&#xA;put the fpaste link in your clipboard automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, I just happen to share a lot of content (code snippets, application or middleware logs, ASCII&#xA;art, you name it!) with other people using both fpaste and pastebin. It makes it easier to read&#xA;text when trying to debug something.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically, I really dislike this format:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
